Wanted: For chicanery, skulduggery, tomfoolery and habitual bungling!
The Apple Dumpling Gang is a comedy, family,
western film directed by Norman Tokar.
A roving bachelor gets saddled with three children and a wealth of
trouble when the youngsters stumble upon a huge gold nugget.
They join forces with two bumbling outlaws to fend off the greedy townspeople
and soon find themselves facing a surly gang of sharpshooters.
Theodore Ogelvie, played by Don Knotts.
Amos Tucker, played by Tim Conway.
Homer McCoy, played by Harry Morgan.
Russel Donavan, played by Bill Bixby.
Magnolia Dusty Clydesdale, played by Susan Clark.
T.R. Clydesdale, played by David Wayne.
The Apple Dumpling Gang is a 1975 American
comedy-Western film directed by Norman Tokar.
It follows a slick gambler named Russell Donovan (Bill Bixby) who is duped
into taking care of three orphans who eventually strike gold.
It was produced by Walt Disney Productions.
The film is based on the 1971 novel of the same name by Jack M.
Don Tait wrote the screenplay.
The so-called "Apple Dumpling Gang" are named after their
favorite American dessert treat, the apple dumpling.
It is also known as being the first film to feature the
comedy duo of Don Knotts and Tim Conway.
Buddy Baker composed the music for the film and its sequel, The Apple Dumpling
Gang Rides Again, with Joseph Dubin performing the orchestration.
The song "The Apple Dumpling Gang", as heard in the opening and closing credits, was composed
by Shane Tatum and was performed by Randy Sparks and the Back Porch Majority.
The tone is lighthearted.